<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
	<id>1.07</id>
	<url>https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training</url>
	<name>FitSM Training</name>
	<tagline>Learn how to manage IT services with a pragmatic and lightweight standard</tagline>
	<description>With FitSM Training you will learn the fundamentals of IT service management and how to implement FitSM in your organisation through a combination of lessons and examples. FitSM is a lightweight standard for IT service management. It brings order and traceability with simple, practical support and provides a common conceptual and process model setting out realistic requirements. The training programme is structured in three levels: Foundation, Advanced and Expert and is accredited by TÜV SÜD, a global leader in standardisation and certification. With FitSM training you can: increase your expertise in managing IT services, raise your professional profile by a recognised certification.</description>
	<options>Foundation Level, Advanced Level in Service Planning and Delivery, Advanced Level in Service Operation and Control, Expert Level, Expert Bridge (Side entry for ITSM professionals)</options>
	<targetUsers>Any organisation that delivers IT services</targetUsers>
	<userValue>Increase your expertise in managing IT services, Increase professional profile by a recognized certification.</userValue>
	<userBase>13 total courses run commercially by EGI, for a total of over 100 certificates released.Following istitutions having received the service: CSC - IT Center for Science, EGI Foundation, EMBL-EBI, German Climate Computing Centre (DKRZ), i2CAT Foundation, INFN (Bologna, LNF, MIB, Pisa, Rome1, Rome2, Torino), Jisc, Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karolinska Institutet, KTH - Royal Institute of Technology, NSC, Pure Purpose, LLC, STFC, SURFnet, SURFsara, Terradue (IT Srl, UK Ltd)</userBase>
	<providers>EGI Foundation</providers>
	<lifeCycleStatus>Production</lifeCycleStatus>
	<trl>9</trl>
	<category>Training</category>
	<subcategory>Face-to-face training</subcategory>
	<request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
	<trainingInformation>http://fitsm.itemo.org/fitsm-training-material</trainingInformation>
	<price>Training events: https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/calendar/In-house training: https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/in-house-training/</price>
	<termsOfUse>https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/terms-and-conditions/</termsOfUse>
	<funding>Operational: Trainings are directly funded through course fees paid by participantsDevelopment: Member of ITEMO (voluntary)</funding>
</service>