<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
	<id>1.1</id>
	<url>"https://www.egi.eu/internal-services/accounting"</url>
	<name>"Accounting"</name>
	<tagline>"Track and report the usage of your services"</tagline>
	<description>"EGI Accounting stores user accounting records from various services offered by EGI, such as Cloud, HTC and storage usage. It works thanks to a network of message brokers that transfer usage data from the host to a central repository of information. The data is handled securely and can be consulted online through the EGI Accounting Portal. EGI council members can use EGI accounting services to account for the resource usage of their own services. EGI Accounting gives: increased control over resource consumption, reduced overhead of defining data models, architecture and setup of an accounting system, reduced cost of maintaining an accounting infrastructure, access to a reliable, high available, high performance service, user friendly web interface."</description>
	<options></options>
	<targetUsers>"User communities and EGI service providers, VO Managers, Resource providers management"</targetUsers>
	<userValue>"Reduced overhead of defining data models, architecture and setup of an accounting system, reduced cost of maintaining an accounting infrastructure."</userValue>
	<userBase>"EGI resource providers: https://www.egi.eu/federation/data-centres/"</userBase>
	<symbol></symbol>
	<multimediaURL></multimediaURL>
	<providers>"EGI Foundation (via EGI resource providers)"</providers>
	<version></version>
	<lastUpdate></lastUpdate>
	<changeLog></changeLog>
	<validFor></validFor>
	<lifeCycleStatus>"Production"</lifeCycleStatus>
	<trl>9</trl>
	<category>"Operations"</category>
	<subcategory>"Αccounting"</subcategory>
	<places></places>
	<languages></languages>
	<tags></tags>
	<requiredServices></requiredServices>
	<relatedServices></relatedServices>
	<request>"https://www.egi.eu/request-service/"</request>
	<helpdesk></helpdesk>
	<userManual></userManual>
	<trainingInformation></trainingInformation>
	<feedback></feedback>
	<price></price>
	<serviceLevelAgreement></serviceLevelAgreement>
	<termsOfUse></termsOfUse>
	<funding>"Development: EC H2020 projects (primarily) and national projects/open source projects. Operations: EGI participant fees + in-kind contribution from service providers"</funding>
</service>