<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
	<id>4.01</id>
	<url>www.openaire.eu</url>
	<name>OpenAIRE Discovery Portal</name>
	<tagline>Find open linked research </tagline>
	<description>The OpenAIRE Discovery portal provides access to Open Access research content. It is based on OpenAIRE's open scholarly communication graph that includes all research and scholarly activitiies, spanning all phases of the research life cycle. The OpenAIRE scholarly communication graph is created bi-monthly by aggregating, cleaning, transforming and inferring content retrieved from OpenAIRE's European and global network of validated OA data providers. In addition to the usual search and browse mechanisms, the OpenAIRE Discovery portal provides end user functionalities which allow users to: find the most fitting repository to deposit their publication or data, authoritavely enrich the underlying content (e.g., linking research results to funding, linking research resultsto external sources), view, download reports or graphs of aggregated research outcomes (e.g., per funder, project, institution) and their stats.</description>
	<targetUsers>Academic community, Research Community, policy makers, funders, research libraries, educators, industry, citizen scientists/public.</targetUsers>
	<userValue>Enable intelligent and contextualized research discovery.Connect public to open access research in Europe and beyond.</userValue>
	<userBase>9,200 registered users. 50,000 users use the service on the average every month. </userBase>
	<providers>OpenAIRE consortium</providers>
	<version>v3</version>
	<lifeCycleStatus>Production</lifeCycleStatus>
	<trl>9</trl>
	<category>Content delivery</category>
	<subcategory>Data linking</subcategory>
	<relatedServices>OpenAIRE Discovery portal is based on a set of OpenAIRE services: - OpenAIRE Aggregation Service- OpenAIRE Inference service- OpenAIRE Research Analytics service- OpenAIRE usage statistics service</relatedServices>
	<request>www.openaire.eu</request>
	<helpdesk>https://www.openaire.eu/support/helpdesk</helpdesk>
	<feedback>https://www.openaire.eu/support/helpdesk</feedback>
	<price>Free</price>
	<funding>EC funding </funding>
</service>