<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
    <id>01.09</id>
    <brandName>FitSM Training</brandName>
    <tagline>Learn how to manage IT services with a pragmatic and lightweight standard</tagline>
    <fullName>Training on Light-weight IT service management based on FiTSM standard</fullName>
    <description>With FitSM Training you will learn the fundamentals of IT service management and how to implement FitSM
        in your organisation through a combination of lessons and examples. FitSM is a lightweight standard for IT
        service management. It brings order and traceability with simple, practical support and provides a common
        conceptual and process model setting out realistic requirements. The training programme is structured in three
        levels: Foundation, Advanced and Expert and is accredited by TÜV SÜD, a global leader in standardisation and
        certification. With FitSM training you can: -Increase your expertise in managing IT services -Raise your
        professional profile by a recognised certification
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Customers: Any organisation that delivers IT services Users: All individuals involved in the
        provisioning of (federated) IT services
    </targetUsers>
    <userValue>- Increase your expertise in managing IT services - Increase professional profile by a recognized
        certification
    </userValue>
    <userBase>13 total courses run commercially by EGI, for a total of over 100 certificates released. Following
        istitutions having received the service: CSC - IT Center for Science, EGI Foundation, EMBL-EBI, German Climate
        Computing Centre (DKRZ), i2CAT Foundation, INFN (Bologna, LNF, MIB, Pisa, Rome1, Rome2, Torino), Jisc, Karlsruhe
        Institute of Technology, Karolinska Institutet, KTH - Royal Institute of Technology, NSC, Pure Purpose, LLC,
        STFC, SURFnet, SURFsara, Terradue (IT Srl, UK Ltd)
    </userBase>
    <provider>EGI Foundation</provider>
    <fundingSources>Operational: Trainings are directly funded through course fees paid by participants Development:
        Member of ITEMO (voluntary)
    </fundingSources>
    <webpage>https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/</webpage>
    <phase>Production</phase>
    <category>Training</category>
    <subcategory>Face-to-face training</subcategory>
    <request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
    <trainingInformation>http://fitsm.itemo.org/fitsm-training-material</trainingInformation>
    <pricing>Training events: https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/calendar/ In-house training:
        https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/in-house-training/
    </pricing>
    <serviceLevelAgreement>See Terms of Use below</serviceLevelAgreement>
    <options>Foundation Level, Advanced Level in Service Planning and Delivery, Advanced Level in Service Operation and
        Control, Expert Level, Expert Bridge (Side entry for ITSM professionals)
    </options>
    <termsOfUse>Terms and Conditions: https://www.egi.eu/services/fitsm-training/terms-and-conditions/</termsOfUse>
</service>