<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
    <id>01.08</id>
    <name>DataHub</name>
    <tagline>Access key scientific datasets scalably</tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>Access selected public datasets and efficiently consume them from EGI compute services. Main features:
        - Discovery of data via a central portal. This will include a searching mechanism plus a rating system which may
        be based on, e.g. number of accesses. - Access to data conforming to required policies which may be: 1)
        unauthenticated open access; 2) access after user registration or 3) access restricted to members of a Virtual
        Organization (VO). This access may be via a GUI (e.g. a url) or an API (e.g. programmatic access to the
        data) - Replication of data from data providers for resiliency and availability purposes. Replication may take
        place either on demand or automatically. Replication will require the introduction of a file catalogue to enable
        tracking of logical and physical copies of data. - Access to data from the AppDB to enable VOs to associate
        appropriate data with matching Virtual Appliances - Authentication and Authorization Infrastructure (AAI)
        integration between the EGI DataHub and with other EGI components and with user communities existing
        infrastructure - File catalogue to track replication of data: logical and physical file
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Customers: research organisations, SME/Industry Users: researchers, innovators</targetUsers>
    <userValue>Easy and efficient access to selected large-scale datasets</userValue>
    <userBase>-Virtual organisations: ICOS, CMS, CTA, EuroBioImaging, Molecular Dynamics Simulations, LBT, eCulture,
        ELIXIR-ITA, EMSO -Earth Observation pilot: RHEA, SixSq, EOProc, CWA, AWS, CESNET and Cyfronet
    </userBase>
    <provider>egi</provider>
    <funding>Development: EC H2020 projects (primarily) and national projects/open source projects. Operations:
        capacity supported by national funding, federation and support co-funded between national funding and EC H2020
        projects
    </funding>
    <url>https://www.egi.eu/services/</url>
    <lifeCycleStatus>Alpha</lifeCycleStatus>
    <trl>7</trl>
    <category>Storage and Data</category>
    <subcategory>Data Management</subcategory>
    <request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
</service>