<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
    <id>01.17</id>
    <name>Operational tools</name>
    <tagline>Integrate resources and operations in a federated ecosystem</tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>The service of Operational tools provides the essential toolkit to run a core infrastructure platform
        in a federated ecosystem. The Operational Tools available for members of the EGI Council are: Monitoring,
        Operations portal, Configuration database, Security tools, Information discovery, Messaging brokers The EGI
        Operational Tools guarantee: - Reduced expenses – the entire tool kit is already available, and maintenance is
        shared by all members. - A predictable service provisioning with high availability and reliability - Full
        operational integration - Increased efficiency of running operations in a federated ecosystem - Easy
        coordination of large collaborations
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Customer: EGI service providers User: NGI Operations Manager, Resource Centre Administrators, VO
        Managers
    </targetUsers>
    <userValue>- Reduced expenses – the entire tool kit is already available, and maintenance is shared by all members.
        - Increased efficiency of running operations in a federated ecosystem - Easy coordination of large
        collaborations
    </userValue>
    <userBase>EGI resource providers: https://www.egi.eu/federation/data-centres/ EGI VO managers</userBase>
    <provider>egi</provider>
    <funding>Development: EC H2020 projects (primarily) and national projects/open source projects. Operations:
        EGI participant fees + in-kind contribution from service providers
    </funding>
    <url>https://www.egi.eu/internal-services/operational-tools/</url>
    <lifeCycleStatus>Production</lifeCycleStatus>
    <trl>9</trl>
    <category>Operations</category>
    <request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
</service>