<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu">
    <id>05.02</id>
    <brandName>PRACE Preparatory Access</brandName>
    <tagline>-</tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>The objective of PRACE Preparatory Access is to allow PRACE users to optimise, scale and test codes on
        PRACE Tier-0 systems before applying to PRACE calls for Project Access. Production runs are not allowed as part
        of PRACE Preparatory Access. Currently, PRACE offers the following schemes for Preparatory Access: Type A: this
        scheme is intended to produce scalability plots of the performance of the codes on PRACE HPC systems, as well as
        other parameters that may be relevant to apply for PRACE calls for Project Access. The maximum duration of Type
        A projects is 2 months. To apply, go here Type B:the objective of this scheme is to undertake code development
        and optimisation. Applicants will need to describe the proposed work plan in detail, including the human
        resources and expertise available to implement the project. The maximum duration of Type B projects is 6 months.
        To apply, go here Type C:in this scheme, PRACE experts are requested to provide the necessary support to
        undertake adaptations (development and optimisation) to the codes of PRACE users. The maximum support that can
        be requested is the equivalent to 6 person-months of effort. The maximum duration of Type C projects is 6
        months. To apply, go here Type D: this scheme allows PRACE users to start a code adaption and optimisation
        process on a PRACE Tier-1 system. PRACE experts help in the system selection process. In addition to Tier-1
        computing time, the PRACE user will also receive Tier-0 computing time towards the end of the project (in form
        of the Type A scheme) to test the scalability improvements. The work is supported by PRACE experts. The maximum
        support that can be requested is the equivalent to 6 person-months of effort. The maximum duration of Type D
        projects is 12 months.
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Scientists and researchers</targetUsers>
    <userValue>Access to Tier-0 resources</userValue>
    <provider>PRACE aisbl</provider>
    <fundingSources>Hosting Members</fundingSources>
    <webpage>http://www.prace-ri.eu/prace-preparatory-access</webpage>
    <phase>Production</phase>
    <technologyReadinessLevel>9</technologyReadinessLevel>
    <category>Compute</category>
    <relatedServices>Project Access</relatedServices>
    <request>http://www.prace-ri.eu/application-guide</request>
    <helpdesk></helpdesk>
    <documentation>http://www.prace-ri.eu/IMG/pdf/Preparatory-Access-ToR_01_02_2017.pdf</documentation>
    <pricing>Free of charge</pricing>
    <termsOfUse>Acceptable use Policies of the hosting sites</termsOfUse>
</service>