<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service>
    <id>01.02</id>
    <brandName>Cloud Compute</brandName>
    <tagline>Run virtual machines on-demand with complete control over computing resources</tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>Cloud Compute gives you the ability to deploy and scale virtual machines on-demand. It offers
        guaranteed computational resources in a secure and isolated environment with standard API access, without the
        overhead of managing physical servers. Cloud Compute offers the possibility to select pre-configured virtual
        appliances (e.g. CPU, memory, disk, operating system or software) from a catalogue replicated across all EGI
        cloud providers. With Cloud Compute you can: - Execute compute- and data-intensive workloads (both batch and
        interactive) - Host long-running services (e.g. web servers, databases or applications servers) - Create
        disposable testing and development environments on virtual machines and scale your infrastructure needs - Select
        virtual machine configurations (CPU, memory, disk) and application environments to fit your requirements -
        Manage your Cloud Compute resources in a flexible way with integrated monitoring and accounting capabilities
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Customers: research organisations, SME/Industry Users: researchers, innovators</targetUsers>
    <userValue>Manage your Cloud Compute resources in a flexible way with integrated monitoring and accounting
        capabilities
    </userValue>
    <userBase>Virtual organisations: ATLAS, CMS, biomed, chipster.csc.fi, d4science.org, enmr.eu, extras, peachnote,
        DARIAH, EMSODEV, NBIS
    </userBase>
    <provider>EGI Foundation (via EGI resource providers)</provider>
    <fundingSources>Development: EC H2020 projects (primarily) and national projects/open source projects. Operations:
        capacity supported by national funding, federation and support co-funded between national funding and EC H2020
        projects
    </fundingSources>
    <webpage>https://www.egi.eu/services/cloud-compute/</webpage>
    <phase>Production</phase>
    <technologyReadinessLevel>9</technologyReadinessLevel>
    <category>Compute</category>
    <subcategory>virtual machine management</subcategory>
    <request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
    <pricing>Free: Researchers meeting policies of the service providers; Pay-for-use: Special technical requirements;
        commercial entity support (beyond initial testing/piloting)
    </pricing>
    <options>Type of instance to host virtual machine (e.g. no. of cores, RAM, local disk)</options>
</service>