<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tns:service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu" xmlns:tns="http://einfracentral.eu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://einfracentral.eu https://builds.openminted.eu/job/eic-registry-model/ws/target/generated-resources/schemagen/schema1.xsd">
    <id>01.04</id>
    <brandName>DIRAC Manager</brandName>
    <tagline>Workload management service to distribute and manage centrally thousands of computational tasks both on
        cloud and HTC
    </tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>DIRAC service is provided to the EGI community as a workload management service used to distribute the
        users' computing tasks among the available resources both HTC and cloud. The service will support established
        Virtual Organization as well as the long tail of users. Main features: - DIRAC provides a High Throughput
        Computing PaaS, which improves the general job throughput compared with native management of grid storage. This
        is possible at DIRAC configuration level, connecting compute and storage resources for particular use
        requirements. - DIRAC File Catalogue includes replica, metadata and provenance functionality simplifying the
        development of scientific application adaptions for distributed environments - DIRAC data and job management
        systems ensure proven production scalability up to peaks of 80 thousand concurrently running jobs for the LHCb
        experiment. This is by far large enough for the computing requirements of environmental science in a sensible
        temporal horizon
    </description>
    <targetUsers>Customers: research organisations, SME/Industry Users: researchers, innovators</targetUsers>
    <userValue>- Retain communities and attract new communities into the dirac.egi.eu service; - Provide more flexible
        VRE simplifying access to EGI resources and accelerate the ability of researches to undertake excellent science
        with DIRAC technical innovations; - Transfer DCI skills and know-how to other medium and big communities and
        resource providers in the context of EGI.
    </userValue>
    <userBase>Virtual organisations: ENWR, VLMED, EISCAT, compchem</userBase>
    <provider>EGI Foundation (via EGI resource providers)</provider>
    <fundingSources>Development: EC H2020 projects (primarily) and national projects/open source projects. Operations:
        capacity supported by national funding, federation and support co-funded between national funding and EC H2020
        projects
    </fundingSources>
    <webpage>https://www.egi.eu/services/</webpage>
    <phase>Alpha</phase>
    <technologyReadinessLevel>7</technologyReadinessLevel>
    <category>Platform</category>
    <subcategory>workload and data manager</subcategory>
    <request>https://www.egi.eu/request-service/</request>
</tns:service>