<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tns:service xmlns="http://einfracentral.eu" xmlns:tns="http://einfracentral.eu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://einfracentral.eu https://builds.openminted.eu/job/eic-registry-model/ws/target/generated-resources/schemagen/schema1.xsd">
    <id>03.09</id>
    <brandName>perfSONAR</brandName>
    <tagline>Real-time, multi-domain performance monitoring​.</tagline>
    <fullName>-</fullName>
    <description>perfSONAR can be used by GÉANT, national research and education networking (NREN) organisations,
        campuses and major projects for quick and easy performance troubleshooting. It provides easy, transparent
        end-to-end monitoring, giving access to network measurement data from multiple network domains. It can operate
        at local level or around the globe and is scalable to provide at-a-glance information about multiple network
        paths simultaneously. By tracking performance across and between domains it is now possible to identify and
        rectify any potential performance bottlenecks, helping research teams focus their efforts on their research and
        allowing NRENs to identify where investments in new capacity will provide the best return. With more than 1,400
        measurement points​ across the globe, it is now far easier for NRENs and research teams to accurately measure
        network performance and ensure it meets their research needs.​ The development of perfSONAR is the result of the
        combined work of GÉANT, Internet2, ESnet and Indiana University.
    </description>
    <targetUsers>NRENs, Campuses, Major networking projects</targetUsers>
    <userValue>PerfSONAR helps distributed project teams monitor their network performance quickly and easily to ensure
        projects can focus on their research and have confidence in the networks they are using. Find out
        how neuGRID​ use perfSONAR to support their international project.
    </userValue>
    <provider>GÉANT</provider>
    <fundingSources>co-funded NREN and H2020 funding (where applicable)</fundingSources>
    <webpage>https://www.geant.org/Services/Connectivity_and_network/Pages/perfSONAR.aspx</webpage>
    <phase>Production</phase>
    <category>Network Performance</category>
    <request>http://www.perfsonar.net/</request>
    <helpdesk>http://www.perfsonar.net/</helpdesk>
    <documentation>http://www.perfsonar.net/</documentation>
    <trainingInformation>http://www.perfsonar.net/</trainingInformation>
    <feedback>http://www.perfsonar.net/</feedback>
    <serviceLevelAgreement>http://www.perfsonar.net/</serviceLevelAgreement>
    <termsOfUse>http://www.perfsonar.net/</termsOfUse>
</tns:service>